

Rohail Butt

- **P** 416-889-1581
- E robutt49@gmail.com
- A 9 Jewel Crescent, Brampton, Ontario, L6R2R1

Dear Hiring Team, January 15, 2023

I am currently pursuing a new career as an IT Technician and would love to have the opportunity to work with Control Play in solving technical problems. For numerous years, I always held a passion for building computer systems, repairing hardware and configuring software. I recently came across your IT & Help Desk Technician posting on indeed and feel I can be a great asset to your team. This is because I believe I can solve many of the technical problems that arise through my preexisting skills in customer service, programming and maintaining operating systems.

My work history involves working as a clinical data analyst and telecommunications for multiple hospitals. This correspondingly led me to sharpen my communication and interpersonal skills to provide outstanding customer service and present clear, concise project reports. I have worked as an operation specialist for a sports memorabilia company and supplied them with multiple outreach methodologies to ably understand customer needs, while consistently raising overall sales each year. The outreach methodologies I utilized contained seminars, presentations, workshops, videos, audio, social media, and cold calls. Recently, I even delivered quality control for the Toronto International Film Festival. By doing so, I processed over 100 digital cinema files to ensure that the content was accurate and will playback during the eleven-day event.

Aside from my work history, whenever I got free time, I would spend my time providing assistance on both the front-end and back-end in building and designing websites for a local digital consulting business. By providing this service, I stockpiled knowledge on human-computer interaction from dealing with multiple clients in industries such as e-commerce and the food catering business.

Overall, my strong communication, time management and technical skills allow me to excel in driving multiple solutions to multiple problems, meet deadlines and remain composed in high-pressure conditions.

I have attached my resume for your review, and I hope to hear from you soon to discuss my candidacy in more detail.

Thank you for your time!

Rohail Butt

Rohail Butt

ROHAIL BUTT

Brampton, ON, CANADA | (416) 889-1581 | robutt49@gmail.com

Objective

Operation Specialist with over 3 years of experience, pursuing a new career as an IT Technician. Experienced in formulating strategies, improving performance, procuring materials and resources, and securing compliance. In addition, a proliferation of skills in web development, quality control, user experience and project management.

Work Experience

SUMMER 2022 - FALL 2022

Quality Control for Toronto International Film Festival / Deluxe

- Delivered 200 + quality control reports for multiple films from varies studios such as Disney, Amazon, and Netflix (identified correct aspect ratios, reviewed coloration gradients, and subtitles being correctly displayed)
- Collaborated with the Scrum teams to run successful release planning, and iterative versions and deployments of multiple movies
- Processed digital cinema hard drives to ensure that content is accurate and will playback successfully during Toronto International Film Festival (Linux and Doremi servers to process the drives)
- Delivered movies and short films to multiple Cinemas in Toronto via electronic delivery, satellite delivery or by physical hard drive

SPRING 2019 - FALL 2022

Operations Specialist / Authentic Memorabilia Company

- Led the task of reconstructing the company's existing rudimentary storage system and designing a new shipment system which increased efficiency by 30%
- Revised product layout and recommended changes in listing products which grew product visibility and sales by 42%
- Maintain front-end and back-end of company's websites and organized a free monthly memorabilia giveaway program to loyal customers
- Provided customer service by managing logistical inbound and outbound orders, shipments, and messaging onboard systems

FALL 2020 - FALL 2021

Multi Hospital Switch Board & Administrator / William Osler Health System

- Directed 300+ telephone calls each shift to the intended departments or medical professionals after screening calls to ensure authenticity
- Collaborated with doctors in an agile project to create a standardized on-call schedule system by providing a project charter, scheduling meetings, and coordinating with multiple stakeholders
- Review performance metrics and KPI with call center team lead to achieve optimal operation goals
 pertaining to patients, vendors, staff, visitors, and external callers
- Provided administrative and clerical support by facilitating interdepartmental communication, managing clinical schedules, and maintaining a digital filing system

Certified Training Specialist / Crunch Fitness Canada

- Developed a project plan that involved free consultations, nutrition sponsorships, fitness classes and hosted monthly health promotion conferences, which increased new membership sales by 20%
- Demonstrated and assisted clients with proper technique in routines to minimize injury and maximize the effectiveness of exercises
- Regularly collected customer feedback and made process changes to exceed customer satisfaction goals each month
- Created paid media such as Google AdWords, and Facebook ads to bring brand awareness

Spring 2016 - Fall 2017

Clinical Data Consultant / Preyra Solutions Group

- Generated tailored reports alongside team leads for diverse stakeholders by using SAS, SQL, Excel (macros, v-lookups, and pivot tables) and PowerPoint
- Advised clients of current trends in different care units across Ontario hospitals such as a potential increase in infections and emergency visits
- Collected multiple data from Ontario hospitals and organized them into electronic databases
- Successful completed multiple performance evaluation projects for various health care organizations across Ontario such as Sick Kids, LHINS, Scarborough, Muskoka, and William Osler

Certifications

SUMMER 2022 - FALL 2022
Google UX Design Foundation Certificate / Coursera

FALL 2021 - WINTER 2022

Google Project Management Professional Certificate / Coursera

Summer 2018 - Fall 2018

Certified Personal Training Specialist / Canadian Fitness Professionals Inc.

Education

SUMMER 2022 - FALL 2022

Python Developer in 2023: Zero to Mastery / Andrei Neagoie

SUMMER 2022 - FALL 2022

CCNA 200-301 Complete Course 2022 / Jeremy's IT Lab

FALL 2013 - FALL 2017

Bachelor of Health Studies with Honours / York University